charitybuzz.com 2014-06-28

# Charitybuzz | Privacy Policy

### Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

Personal Information (PI) is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person.

You may be asked to provide your personal information anytime you are in contact with Charitybuzz. Our company may share this personal information with affiliate or partnering non profits and corporations consistent with this Privacy Policy. Charitybuzz may also combine it with other information to provide and improve our products, advertisement services, content and customer service.

Here are some examples of the types of personal information Charitybuzz may collect and how we may use it.

### What personal information we collect

  * When you create a Charitybuzz account, register your credit card, apply for, purchase a product, register for an email newsletter at the Charitybuzz.com website, we may collect a variety of information, including your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, contact preferences, and credit card information.
  * When you share your content with family and friends using Charitybuzz products, send gift certificates and products, or invite others to join you on Charitybuzz, Charitybuzz may collect the information you provide about those people such as name, mailing address, email address, and phone number. Email addresses will be collected via forms on www.Charitybuzz.com; any other information will be collected via an offline manner. This information is only used to redeem auction lots and is then disposed of, beyond financial and shipping record keeping.
  * In the US we may ask for your Social Security number (SSN) but only in limited circumstances such as when setting up a background check for the high profile celebrity experiences when determining and ensuring safety of our partnering celebrities. We do not store this information in our system but we may share this information with your written permit with a certified third party completing the background check. This information will be collected in an offline manner.

### How we use your personal information

  * The personal information we collect allows us to keep you posted on Charitybuzz's latest product announcements, software updates, and upcoming events. It also helps us to improve our services, content, and advertising. If you don't want to be on our mailing list, you can opt out anytime by [updating your preferences](https://www.charitybuzz.com/account) in your user account or contacting us at [unsubscribe@Charitybuzz.com](mailto:unsubscribe@Charitybuzz.com).
  * From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about purchases and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information is important to your interaction with Charitybuzz, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.
  * We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve Charitybuzz's products, services, and customer communications.

### Collection and Use of Non-Personally Identifying Information (NPPI)

We also collect non-personally identifying information − data in a form that does not permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

  * We may collect information such as occupation, language, zip code, area code, unique device identifier, location, and the time zone where Charitybuzz services are used so that we can better understand customer needs, assist celebrities and improve our products, services, and advertising.
  * We also may collect information regarding customer activities on our website, like time you spent on the site as well as list of previously purchased products, services and experiences you are interested in. This information is aggregated and used to help us provide better customer service to our clients and to understand which parts of our website, products, and services are of most interest. Aggregated data is considered non-personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

If we do combine non-personally identifying information with personally identifying information the combined information will be treated as personal information for as long as it remains combined.

### Cookies and Other Technologies

Charitybuzz's website, online services, interactive applications, and advertisements may use "cookies" and other technologies such as pixel tags and web traffic and meta-tags. These technologies help us understand user behavior, tell us which parts of our website people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

The use of cookies by our [partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers] is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our [partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers] use session ID cookies [to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.] 

Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers’ or Users’ personal information. 

Charitybuzz utilizes cookies and other technologies in mobile advertising services to control the number of times you see a given ad, deliver ads that relate to your interests, and measure the effectiveness of ad campaigns. If you do not want to receive ads with this level of relevance on your mobile device, you can opt out by emailing [unsubscribe@Charitybuzz.com](mailto:unsubscribe@Charitybuzz.com) from the address you wish to have opted out.

If you opt out, you will not receive the newsletters or mobile ads. This unsubscribe option applies only to Charitybuzz advertising services and does not affect interest-based advertising from other advertising networks.

Charitybuzz gathers some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click-stream data.

This information is used to analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Charitybuzz may use this information in our marketing and advertising services.

In some of our email messages, we use a "click-through URL" linked to content on the Charitybuzz website. When customers click one of these URLs, they pass through a separate Charitybuzz web server before arriving at the destination page on our website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages.

Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they tell us whether mail has been opened. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate messages sent to customers.

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies (or Flash LSO’s), to store your preferences such as volume control or high game score, or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118). 

### Disclosure to Third Parties

At times Charitybuzz may make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with Charitybuzz to provide products and services, or that help Charitybuzz market to customers. Charitybuzz shares personal information with companies who provide services such as information processing, shipping, fulfilling customer orders, delivering products to you, managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service, assessing your interest in our products and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are obligated to protect your information and may be located wherever Charitybuzz operates. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

### Others

It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for Charitybuzz to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our user agreement or protect our operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party.

### Protection of Personal Information

Charitybuzz takes precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

Charitybuzz online services such as the Charitybuzz.com online auctions and Charitybuzz The Goods store utilize Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption on all web pages where personal information is collected. To make purchases from these services, you must use an SSL-enabled browser such as Safari, Firefox, or Internet Explorer. Doing so protects the confidentiality of your personal information while it's transmitted over the Internet.

When you use some Charitybuzz products, services, or applications or post on an Charitybuzz forum, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these instances. For example, if you list your name and email address in a forum posting, that information is public. Please take care when using these features.

### Integrity and Retention of Personal Information

Charitybuzz makes it easy for you to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

### Access to Personal Information

You can help ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up to date by logging in to your account at www.Charitybuzz.com and click on the account login. For other personal information, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access so you can request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or delete the data if Charitybuzz is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Access, correction, or deletion requests can be made directly via email to [privacy@Charitybuzz.com](mailto:privacy@Charitybuzz.com). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. 

### Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 16 year of age we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

### Security

Charitybuzz.com is a Thawte® secured website and uses a Thawte® SSL Certificate for encryption. Customer data is securely transmitted by Charitybuzz.com to non-affiliated third-parties as permitted by this privacy policy or by law and to service providers through a combination of encryption techniques and other privacy protection measures. Selected NPPI submitted through the Charitybuzz.com website such as your debit or credit card numbers, expiration dates are encrypted for security reasons. Charitybuzz also maintains and enforces strict internal policies to protect NPPI from unauthorized access by employees or third-parties.

### Location-Based Services

To provide location-based services on Charitybuzz products, Charitybuzz and our partners and licensees may collect, use, and share precise location data, including the real-time geographic location of your Charitybuzz computer or device. This location data is collected anonymously in a form that does not personally identify you and is used by Charitybuzz and our partners and licensees to provide and improve location-based products and services. For example, we may share geographic location with application providers when you opt in to their location services.

### Third-Party Sites and Services

Charitybuzz websites, products, applications, and services may contain links to third-party websites, products, and services. Our products and services may also use or offer products or services from third parties − for example, a third-party iPhone app. Information collected by third parties, which may include such things as location data or contact details, is governed by their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties.

### Widgets

Our website includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

### Facebook Connect or other OpenID provider

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this website to your profile page to share with others within your network.

### Testimonials/Comments/Reviews

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our website which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

### Blogs

If you use our blog on this website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

### International Users

Information you provide may be transferred or accessed by entities around the world as described in this Privacy Policy. Charitybuzz abides by the international credit card merchant laws and complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union and Switzerland respectively. Information regarding the both the E.U. and Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks can be found at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>.

### Our Companywide Commitment to Your Privacy

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our privacy and security guidelines to Charitybuzz employees and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company.

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Privacy Questions

If you have questions or concerns regarding Charitybuzz's Privacy Policy or data processing, please contact us at 437 Fifth Avenue, 11th Floor New York, NY 10016. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request), or by fax at 415-520-3420 or mail to TRUSTe Safe Harbor Compliance Dept., [click for mailing address](http://www.truste.com/about-TRUSTe/contact-us). If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, [click here](http://www.truste.com/products-and-services/dispute-resolution-services/) or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English.
